We are working on congenital muscular dystrophies,
which are genetic disorders of muscles
that are present at birth.
We are particularly working on a  type called
collagen VI-related congenital muscular dystrophy,
which are severe types, also known as
Ullrich congenital muscular dystrophy.
This is caused by mutations in the collagen VI genes.
There are 3 collagen VI genes and mutations
in the collagen VI genes can cause this disease.
We are trying to understand how the mutations
cause the disease and what you can do about it.
So for the collagen VI genes, it is interesting that
mutations are often acting as a dominant,
meaning they are causing a toxic product from
the mutant gene that interferes with the normal collagen VI.
We are devising fair pieces, trying to detoxify
the muscle from this product, the mutant product.
We are trying to "knock down" the mutation readout
from the mutant genes using oligo-nuclear type saRNA,
and all of the CRISPR cross approaches.
That is particularly relevant for a new and common mutation,
that we found in collagen VI,
which is a deep intronic mutation,
a mutation that has been hidden from our analysis so far,
and that causes a pseudo-exon and a toxic pseudo-exon,
to be spliced into the collagen VI gene.
We are trying to skip that out using oligo-nuclear type therapies.
This is a highly individualised therapy,
so we have to devise a therapy for each individual mutation
that we find in the collagen VI genes.
This is really a prime example of precision medicine,
or tailor-made medicine for a particular mutation
for a particular patient.
So that is the goal, in our laboratories,
to be precise about the diagnosis leading
to precise therapies for individual patients.
Organisations like the AFM will play a big role
in making possible that therapies become available
for even mutations that are very rare,
and for patients that are not large in number,
and so that is a project that by necessity
has to be funded by public funds,
by patient advocacy
and the AFM will play a big role in
making possible that the research
can really go down
to the level of the individual patients.