I'm working on a rather rare muscle disease
called GNE myopathy.
In the past, it was called also
hereditary inclusion body myopathy,
or distal myopathy with rimmed vacuoles.
It's an adult-onset myopathy
beginning in the distal muscles of the legs,
and slowly progressing to affect
the upper limbs too.
Usually the onset is in the early adulthood,
and the disease progresses slowly
over several decades,
leading to a marked disability over the years.
We recently had a phase-3 trial.
In fact this is the first phase-3 trial
in distal myopathy
that was conducted, and unfortunately,
it did not show any improvement
with supplementation of sialic acid,
which was thought to be
the cause of the disease — i.e. the deficiency,
The difficulty in that study was that
this was a short study compared
to the disease progression,
and that people were very variable
in the severity of their disorders:
Some of them were more rapidly progressing
as compared to others, and because of that,
the supplementation did not show
a positive effect in this trial.
The message is that despite the fact
that this trial has helped,
we have not stopped trying.
First of all, we have learned a few things
from the supplementation with sialic acid,
and a rather similar metabolic approach
is now underway in the United States,
learning from previous problems
that we had in the study,
including outcome measures,
how to follow patients and for how long...
We had in fact a joint meeting, a workshop,
with all leaders in this field,
to try and find a common way of collaboration,
because this is a rare disease,
but it is clustered in some ethnic populations,
which need to be approached.
Some of those are not privileged people,
and because of that, it is hard to conduct
a study in such a population.
However, the disease is a worldwide disease,
and there are probably a couple of dozens
of patients here in France too.