We have been studying myostatin inhibition
for a variety of muscle disorders, which include
Duchenne, Becker's,
facio-scapulo-humeral muscular dystrophies,
limb-girdle muscular dystrophies,
and sporadic IBM.
So myostatin is a natural inhibitor
of muscle growth.
It circulates in the body
and keeps muscle growth in check.
When you inhibit myostatin,
you get increased muscle growth, increased strength,
and an improvement in muscle quality,
that is less fibrosis or scarring of tissue.
And so this has been really, very promising
in animal models, and now has been translated
into human clinical trials.
There has been several different types
of myostatin inhibitors being trialled
in muscular dystrophies and myopathies.
The AFM has been incredibly helpful
in organizing and motivating, and
propelling research forward
in the neuromuscular disorders.
The meeting today...
has really been very successful.
The AFM has organized and funded,
bringing together researchers from around the world
to discuss the latest in myopathies.
The AFM also funds
a significant amount of research
and is really at the forefront
of bringing these novel therapies to patients.