My lab works mostly on Duchenne muscular dystrophy.
Today at the conference, I spoke about
two different approaches
to treating Duchenne muscular dystrophy,
two different gene-therapy based approaches.
The first of these is called surrogate gene therapy.
In surrogate gene therapy we don't try to replace
the missing gene, the missing dystrophin protein.
We instead use a substitute gene,
one that can substitute in function for it.
And the gene we use is called GALGT2.
GALGT2 is a protein that is normally expressed
at the dystroglycan complex.
It was called the neuromuscular junction,
where nerve meets muscle.
And in that place, dystrophin protein
does not bind to the complex.
Instead, a different protein called utrophin does.
That is where GALGT2 is usually found.
So it turns out that we overexpress,
if we deliver GalGT2,
the muscle will make the same complex
occur across the entire muscle memory,
sort of make utrophin substitute for dystrophin.
It actually makes other proteins
that are important for stabilising the muscles.
It turned out as well.
So that is the surrogate gene approach,
and tomorrow we will be doing it in clinical trials in patients, the substitute.
The second thing I talked about
was a way of combining exon skipping
and gene therapy.
So in this case we use a virus,
the AAV virus.
We use that virus to deliver
a form of RNA
that never gets turned into a new protein.
But that RNA that we deliver,
called the U7 small nuclear RNA
can interfere with splicing.
It interferes with splicing very efficiently.
So in that case, we are directing our splicing RNA,
we just direct it to exon 2
and we have learned that we can highly efficiently
skip a duplicated copy of exon 2.
As a result, we can make
a perfectly normal dystrophin...
or if we skip too much,
we make a kind of dystrophin
that is really very protective.
That allows for example people
who walk around making that type of dystrophin...
They walk into their seventh decade
or their eighth decade.
So it is really very functional.
We call it "virally-mediated exon skipping".
It is something first developed here in France,
with funding from the AFM long ago,
and we now applied it to exon 2
for Duchenne muscular dystrophy.
The AFM is a terrific organisation
that has a world-wide impact
in the study and treatment of neuro-muscular diseases
and Duchenne muscular dystrophy in particular.
I first learned of the AFM years ago
when I was first in laboratory
working with the agency that developed the Genethon.
Since then I had a terrific, long interaction
with the AFM,
and the AFM helped to fund a sabbatical year
that I did here in Paris at the institute of Myology,
which really is one of the world's leading institutions for
the coordinated care in research in the muscle diseases.
And I continue to have close interactions
with Genethon and the Institute of Myology
and other researches from the AFM.
I look forward to cementing,
to building on this relationship
in the coming years as well.